William F. Raborn Papers
William F. Raborn Papers
1916-1963
Raborn, William F., 1905-1990.
8.0 linear ft.
U.S. naval officer, Admiral. Collection contains correspondence (1945-1963); speeches, calendars (1961-1962), photographs, scrapbooks, and audio tapes.
149535
Biographical History
William F. Raborn, Jr. (1905-1990) was a career military officer, a Navy vice admiral who led the development of the Polaris nuclear missile in the 1950s and later headed the Central Intelligence Agency under President Lyndon B. Johnson.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William F. Raborn Papers consist of correspondence, general files, personal files and memorabilia. Correspondence is made up of such communiques as sympathy letters, orders, and letters of congratulation. General files consists of material relating to Raborn's Navy career. Personal files is made up of non-career material. Memorabilia contains awards, photographs, tape recordings, and a navigation instrument.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically. All other material is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Military history; Raborn, William F., 1905-1990.; United States. -- Navy -- History.; United States. -- Navy -- Officers.; Admirals -- United States.; United States -- History, Naval -- 20th century.; Audiotapes.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Speeches (documents); Admirals.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Personal, 1945-1963; 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Orders, 1951-1963 (Box 1)
  - Polaris missile firing, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Vice Admiral appointment, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Condolence letters, 1954; 1962 (Box 1)
- General files
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Electronics (Box 1)
  - Flag officers (Box 1)
  - Interviews (Box 1)
  - Polaris (Box 1)
  - Program Evaluation and Review Technique (PERT) (Box 1)
  - Research and development (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 3 folders (Box 2)
- Personal files
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Captain William F. Raborn, Jr., 2 folders (Box 2)
- Memorabilia
  - Art reproduction (Oversize 5)
  - Awards, engagements (Box 2)
  - Awards, oversize (Oversize 5)
  - Books
    - Bible (Box 2)
    - Daily engagement books, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - Engineering Mark's Handbook, 1916 (Box 2)
    - Flight book (aviator's), 3 volumes (Box 2)
    - Speaking engagements book, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Button (Box 3)
  - Cartoons (Oversize 5)
  - Inspector's notebook and papers (Box 3)
  - Letter (Oversize 5)
  - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous printed material (Oversize 3)
  - Navigation instrument (Box 3)
  - Patch (Box 3)
  - Sash (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks, 3 volumes (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks, oversize (Oversize 4)
  - Photographic material
    - Color transparencies (Oversize 1)
    - Photographs (Box 4)
    - Photographs (Oversize 2)
    - Photographs (Oversize 3)
    - Photographs (Oversize 4)
    - Photographs (Oversize 5)
    - Negatives (Box 4)
    - Plates (Box 4)
    - Slides, 3 boxes (Box 4)
    - Films, 16mm, 2 rolls (Box 4)
  - Recordings
    - Discs, 8 items (Box 4)
    - Tapes, 12 reels (Box 4)
    - Tapes, 39 reels (Box 5)
  - Films, miscellaneous, 4 reels (Box 6)